8 SE 9th Avenue Deerfield Beach, FL 33441 (954) 449-3848 ARodrigu02@yahoo.com

#### JR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Information Technology professional with over 10 years' experience in technical support and configuration management in transition to .NET development. Recent graduate of LaunchCode LC101, a coding fundamentals program. CCNA Cyber Ops and CompTIA A+/Network+/Security+ certified. Bilingual (English/Spanish).

#### **CORE STRENGTHS**

C#, .NET Core 3.1, ASP NET MVC Core 3 CCNA, CompTIA A+/Network+/Security+ Windows 7, 8, 10/Unix/Linux

Tools Support Desktop Support Troubleshooting Superior Customer Service Strong Interpersonal Skills Excellent Communicator

## **COMPUTER SKILLS**

**Software**: Visual Studio 2019, Microsoft SQL Server 2008, SQL Server Management Studio, MySQL, IBM Rational Clearcase/Multisite.

**Operating Systems**: UNIX (AIX, HP-UX, OSF1), Windows XP/Vista/Win7/Win8/Win10, Linux.

**Languages**: C#, .NET Core 3.1, ASP NET MVC Core 3, ADO.NET, LINQ, XHTML, CSS, Java, Java Servlets and JSP, JavaScript, JQuery, ANSI C, C++.

**Scripting Languages**: Bourne, ksh, Perl, Python, sed, awk, make.

**Cyber security**: Attack Methods, Data and Event Analysis, Endpoint Threat Analysis, Network Intrusion Analysis. **QA Essentials**: Charles (HTTP Proxy), Firebug, Flashblock, HttpFox, iMacros for Firefox, Web Developer, Notepad++. **Blogger's Tools**: Search Engine Optimization (SEO) principles, AdWords, Google Analytics, WordPress, and Social Media. **Certifications**: CCNA Cyber Ops, CompTIA A+/Network+/Security+.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**SUBSTITUTE MATHEMATICS TEACHER**, The School Board of Broward County, Ft. Lauderdale, FL

2012 - 2015

Substitute mathematics teacher in Broward County, FL. Taught math, implemented lesson plans, and managed classroom of 28 students of various abilities.

## INTERNET BUSINESS CONSULTANT, My Cuban Recipes, Deerfield Beach, FL

2010 - 2013

Owner and operator of MyCubanRecipes.com, a didactic blog for those interested in Cuban cuisine, with 2500 visitors per month. Site no longer in operation.

# QA ANALYST, MotionPoint, Coconut Creek, FL

2009 - 2009

Performed QA on translated web sites with emphasis on look, feel, and functionality, with respect to the original web site.

• Conducted thorough analysis of content and technologies employed on several key clients' web sites to determine potential technical challenges encountered during translation process into target languages, resulting in significant cost savings to MotionPoint, faster product delivery, and lower maintenance costs to clients.

## IT CONTRACTOR, Pound Interactive, Boca Raton, FL

2008 - 2008

Responsible for carrying out quality assurance functions on client web sites; acted as backup release engineer; and performed regular updates and upgrades to development tools, from 6/2008 to 10/2008.

- Performed exhaustive testing of commercial web sites prior to production release, thus significantly contributing to the quality of the product and the reputation of the company.
- Amended and documented a repeatable verifiable release process, greatly enhancing reliability and consistency of baselines.

## SALES ASSOCIATE, Coldwell Banker, Parkland, FL

2005 - 2006

Worked in residential sales guiding customers through the task of purchasing a home.

# INTERIM MATHEMATICS TEACHER, Spanish River Community High, Boca Raton, FL

2004 - 2004

Taught geometry and algebra to 150 ESOL students of diverse nationalities and various abilities; prepared and implemented appropriate lesson plans to facilitate the learning of all students.

## IT CONTRACTOR, Motorola, Plantation, FL

2002 - 2003

Responsible for building and releasing software for 10 mobile radio products, as a contractor for Technisource, Ft. Lauderdale, FL; formulated software configuration management plans; performed baseline setup for 10 new projects; and developed Perl scripts to automate CM processes.

- Fine-tuned makefiles to take full advantage of ClearCase's build avoidance algorithm. Changes resulted in a 50% reduction in build times.
- Modified custom Perl build scripts to allow for a gradual update of all the makefiles without impacting 100's of weekly builds.

# TOOLS SUPPORT ENGINEER, Siemens, Boca Raton, FL

1999 - 2001

Provided timely support to 100's of ClearCase users on both UNIX and NT platforms; evaluated, selected, and integrated CASE tools into development environment; designed, wrote, and tested Bourne, ksh, and Perl scripts; and published the Tools Services Group web pages to inform users and disseminate metrics reports.

- Selected and integrated CASE tools into development environment, resulting in a 20% 50% increase in productivity of software developers.
- Designed, wrote, and tested Bourne, ksh, and Perl scripts to automate merging of directories and files, thereby increasing consistency and reliability of production baselines by 50%.

## TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER, Citibank, Ft. Lauderdale, FL

1995 - 1999

Provided round the clock support for on-line transaction processing (OLTP) banking system for Latin America; installed, configured, and supported IBM Rational ClearCase for a 30-member development staff; and contributed to the design and implementation of the OLTP banking system for Latin America, employing C++, Oracle, and Oasis IST Switch - a leading transaction processing software solution.

- Quickly identified problems with OLTP and devised and implemented solutions, thus minimizing costly disruptions of service to Citibank's customers.
- Key participant in team that implemented SEI's CMMI.
- Developed ClearCase training materials and instructed users on ClearCase best practices, saving Citibank \$20,000 in consulting fees.
- Designed, wrote, and tested Bourne, ksh, and Perl scripts to automate CM processes, thus increasing productivity by 50%.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Florida International University**, Miami, FL, M.S. Mathematics Education; Graduated with Honors **Florida International University**, Miami, FL, B.S. Computer Science; Graduated with Highest Honors **University of Miami**, Coral Gables, FL, B.S. Electrical Engineering; Graduated Magna Cum Laude